# William "Tim" Curtis

## Software Developer

**:** (931)-265-0796

inkedin/william-t-curtis

 $\leq$ 

: Timcurtis97@yahoo.com

: Github/tcurtis97

#### **Skills**

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React.js | Bootstrap | Scrum/Agile | Github | C#/.Net | SOL

### **Projects**

Penny Pinch | Individual Project | View Code

Penny Pinch is a budgeting application used to keep track of monthly spending. Penny Pinch gives the users the tools to organize expenses and view their difference between incoming and outgoing income.

- Single-page app has full CRUD functionality and was created utilizing React, React Router, and API fetch calls to JSON server
- Styling was achieved through CSS and Bootstrap to create a simple, user -friendly experience

#### Education

Nashville Software School, Software Developer Bootcamp | Certificate

Tennessee College of Applied Technology, — Heating, Air Conditioning, Ventilation and Refrigeration

#### **Profile**

Prior to beginning my journey in software development, I worked as a tradesperson. I enjoyed working in a field that allowed me to use my skills to build structures and systems people used in their everyday life. It allowed me to solve complex problems using logic while working in a team environment. I enjoy working in a field that lets me hone my skills, and there is always something new to learn or a new problem to solve. When a friend introduced me to software development, I realized that the tech field would allow me to experience the same fulfillment and work I enjoyed, while not being so physically wearing on my body. This started my love of software that has continued to grow with every new technology I encounter.

#### **Experience**

## Software Developer Nashville Software School

(November 2020 - Present)

Intensive full-time software development boot camp focusing on full-stack development fundamentals and problem solving where I participated and lead group and individual projects. Developed in C# .NET framework on back end and React.js on the front end.

- Git and GitHub for version control
- · Simulated agile work environment
- Experience in remote collaboration
- Created one page applications using diverse tech stacks including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.Js, Reactstrap/Bootstrap, C#, .Net, MVC, SQL

#### Installer

Curtis Brothers Construction (2015 - 2016) (May 2018 - Present)

Industrial construction company specializing in In-Plant Modular Offices, Clean Rooms, Steel Mezzanine Systems, Industrial Storage Racking, Industrial Shelving, Conveyor Systems, Ergonomic Gorbel Cranes, R&M cranes, and a variety of Material Handling Components.

- Installed modular buildings, modular clean rooms, modular wall partitions, industrial curtain walls, mezzanines, pallet rack, and cranes.
- Installed VRC elevators
- Installed heating, cooling, and ventilation systems for modular cleanrooms
- Installed drop ceilings in each modular building
- Operated forklift, lull forklift, scissor lift, articulating boom lift
- Operated on team and built invaluable communication skills to complete large and daunting tasks safely and efficiently
- Worked with salesman and customers to make coherent plans to complete jobs while managing to meet customer needs